[bright music]
So how have you been?
You know, I tried to reach out
to you for a couple of months.
But you weren’t responding.
You weren’t answering my calls.
Yeah, same here.
Yeah, um…
I’m sorry about that. I just, um...
It was... It was really
hard after the breakup.
It’s alright. It’s been over a year.
Have you reached out to Ivan and Dave?
Alright, I understand.
Let’s not talk about them.
And let’s talk about you.
I know you have something to tell us.
First, do you need anything?
Cause I’d be more than
happy to help. Just let me know.
Well, I’m seeing someone right now.
- Alright. - Okay.
That’s... good. Who is he?
He’s my roommate.
Yeah, um...
We’ve been living together
for a few weeks now.
Oh, Interesting.
Wow, yeah. Tell us… Tell us more.
Well...
he just proposed.
Over...
coffee and bread and hotdogs.
I'm...
- I’m so sorry. I didn’t mean to make…
- No, no. It's... It's okay.
I... I think about it, too.
And I can’t help but...
Wait, what are you gonna do?
[soft music]
I don’t know.
Do you...
Do you like him?
Uh,
I guess so, yeah.
Guess? But do you like him enough to...
you know.
I’m not even sure if I’m ready for-
Honey, no, no, no…
Hey, it’s okay. Don’t cry.
Listen, you’ve been through a lot.
You... You deserve to be happy.
What I’m about to say is just
based on my personal experience.
You know we love you.
And you know we’re for you.
Even though you chose to stay away
from us after your breakup with Ivan.
I think, before you make
any other major life decisions,
you need to let go.
You need to learn how to let go.
You need to forgive Ivan.
And most importantly,
you need to forgive yourself.
You just loved someone too much.
[dramatic music]
Hey, where have you been?
I’ve been waiting for you.
And listen, about what
I said earlier, just...
forget about it.
I was being stupid and -
You should go home.
What?
You should go back to the Philippines.
You’re drunk. And you don’t
know what you’re saying.
Let’s talk about this tomorrow.
You’re tired. You need some rest.
No. I... I know what I’m saying just fine.
And I want you to fucking leave.
This is about the proposal, right?
Don’t worry about it. I spoke
to the immigration lawyer.
And I have other options.
I don’t care what the fucking lawyer said.
I want you to go home.
I want you to go back to Manila.
I’ll book the flight if I have to.
I’ll do it myself.
Just get out.
Joshua, please.
- Joshua, please. - No, no.
Joshua...
I shouldn’t have done what I did.
- I’m sorry and I just - - Let me go.
Promise I won’t do
anything that stupid again.
Please.
Don’t make me leave.
[soft music]
Why do you want to stay?
You can’t even tell me
why you want to stay.
Because I want to be with you!
Fuck you!
You barely know me.
You have a great life
back in the Philippines.
You’re... You're making
films. You’re winning awards.
And you want to throw all of
that away just to be with me?
And… And your Mom.
She did other people’s laundry when you
were growing up just to make ends meet.
And now, she’s out in the Middle East,
God only knows if she’s safe.
Just to support you and whatever
you want to do with your fucking life.
And you want to throw...
You want to throw away
all her years of sacrifice
just to be with some guy
you’ve only known a few weeks?
Because that’s for her. For my dreams.
Well, you can’t work here.
[soft music]
Which is why I asked you to marry me.
Well, I can’t marry you.
Why?
Because I’m already married!
I was young and stupid.
And I was only thinking
about how I felt about him.
He was… He was also a visitor like you.
And he was also afraid of overstaying.
And he said he couldn’t achieve
his dreams if he was illegal.
And so I was over here, uh,
trying to be a hero.
Trying to be a savior.
And I agreed to marry him.
I thought if I give him what he needed,
that everything would be fine and
we would be happy together forever.
But a few months after our wedding,
I found out he’s cheating on me.
Do you know how badly I
wanted to get back at him?
How... How badly I
wanted to make him suffer.
To make him feel the way he made me feel.
And it would be so easy.
All I have to do, right
now, is file for divorce.
Because then, he
couldn’t get his green card.
He needs to be married to me for two years.
And he couldn’t even stay with me for one.
Fucking idiot.
Left me for someone with a lot more money.
It’s just like I said, it’s always
just been about the money!
And you know what the most painful part is?
I still
care about him.
And I hate that I care so much
about him after what he did to me.
But I do.
I think about him all the fucking time.
I'm thinking about how he’s doing.
Is he okay? Is he happy?
Is all the money worth it?
And I’m sorry, but
you deserve to know this.
I still think about him
even when I’m with you.
[crying]
[dramatic music]
[soft music]
Bestfriend, get up.
What are you doing here?
Don't start with me! Get up!
What's the matter with you?
Nothing. But you, you've
got a lot of problems!
Leave me alone!
Be grateful, you're handsome or else
I would've punched you in the face!
Your so annoying!
Your mom keeps on calling me.
She's worried sick.
You're not responding to her.
I just told her that you're busy
with the script you're working on.
Who told you to do that?
Why don't you all go to hell? F♪ck you all!
Fuck you, too!
Damn you!
You're just going to end up like that?
Wasted all the time?
Well, you're not a kid anymore, Andre.
You're wasting a lot of opportunities!
Stop blaming that f♪ucking love
for why your life's so wasted!
You've only got yourself to blame!
And only you can help
yourself, no one else!
[crying]
I can't forget him.
That moment when I left him
knowing how miserable he was.
I wonder how he's doing now.
The memories of him
keep on haunting me.
Bestfriend,
if you're really worried about him,
it's best to work on yourself first.
How can you help him if
you can't even help yourself?
[soft music]
If I were you,
I'd finish your film project.
Attend another film festival in America.
So you could see and visit him again.
But if you're wasted all the time,
nothing will happen.
Life has to continue moving
forward even if you're lonely.
F♪ck that scammer!
I shouldn't have met Joshua.
Why don't you write to him?
Email him.
Curse him all you want.
Let him know how you feel.
Believe me, bestfriend,
it's very effective.
Of all the things I've been through,
it's the most effective way to let go.
[soft music]
And I always remind you, bestfriend,
just because you love someone
doesn't mean they'll love you in return.
Life’s not like that.
[soft music]
Hi Joshua,
I am writing this email
because I want to say
fuck you!
I didn’t deserve what you did to me!
Being hurt doesn’t give you
the right to hurt other people!
I have nothing to do with your past!
I am not the one who cheated on you!
And if I were, I’d stop blaming
other people for your own misery.
Hi, Joshua.
I hope you’re okay.
I know we were not able to
properly say goodbye to each other.
And I’m sorry for that.
I chose to leave before I had
the chance to fully understand
what you’ve been going through.
[soft music]
I chose to get mad at you
when what you really needed
was a shoulder to cry on.
I haven’t even thanked you for
all the things you’ve done for me.
When I was looking for a place to stay,
you let me into yours.
You chose to help me many times,
even when you were the one who needed help.
You were suffering, bleeding on the inside,
but you never cried for help.
You seemed so strong,
I didn’t realize
that worse things were happening to you.
You chose to love me at a time when
you didn’t have that much love to give.
You were right about one thing,
I’ve been selfish.
I didn’t realize how lucky I am.
Because there are people in my
life who keep on cheering for me
no matter how much I screw up.
Listen, you’ve been through a lot.
[soft music]
And I will forever regret
not staying behind
when you needed me the most.
I really missed you, Joshua.
I hope I get to see you again.
And
I’m going to do my best
to make that happen.
I just hope that when the time comes,
I’m a little more mature
and maybe can give you
what you actually deserve.
For now,
I’m just gonna think of
our memories together.
And I don’t know if this helps
but
just know that someone,
thousands of miles away,
still cares about you.
[dramatic music]
Hello?
Who’s this? Don't... Don’t you
know it’s two in the morning?
Oh.
Hi, Josh...
ua.
Where are you going?
And don’t tell me work?
It’s already ten at night.
No, I’m meeting Bob and Wayne.
Mm... Good!
And where are you guys headed to?
Ahh...
Some bar in We-Ho.
Oh, so you’re…
you’re gonna be partying in We-Ho?
Is there something wrong with that?
No, uh...
why would there be?
You should go out as much as you like.
I just…
I just wish I could join you guys.
Ahh...
So when are you coming?
What?
Uh, well,
actually, I have some good news for you.
Okay.
Just make sure it’s really a good news.
It is.
Uh,
My first feature film,
the project I’ve been working
on for the past year and a half,
it’s officially been accepted
into a festival in New York.
Okay, uh...
Well,
New York is far.
Oh, really?
Yeah, I mean, it’s…
it’s on the other coast.
I have to go soon. But just
tell me when the
festival’s going to happen,
So I can take a leave.
Uh, one week, two weeks,
I don’t care.
I’ll be there.
Bye.
Oh wait, wait, before you go…
Well,
bye Josh...
ua.
[dramatic music]